symantecstore.com 2014-06-27

# Complete Privacy Policy | Symantec

#### Your Privacy Rights

_Last Updated: August 12, 2013_

 **[Update]** On June 1, 2013, we updated our data collection and use disclosure under the cookies' section (3.2) and subsections (3.2.1, 3.2.2, 3.2.3, 3.2.5, 3.2.6).

 **[Update]** On December 5, 2012, we updated our data collection and use practices (Section 3.1) and added new cookies (Sections 3.2.1, 3.2.2, 3.2.3, 3.2.5).

This Statement describes the types of information we collect via Symantec’s web sites as set out below, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Statement also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. We also tell you how you may contact us to update your information, remove your name from our mailing lists or get answers to questions you may have about our privacy practices at Symantec.

[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.symantec.com&sealid=101) Symantec has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy Statement and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe certifies the sites **www.symantec.com** in North America, **www.symanteccloud.com** , and **Norton domains.** The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. You may contact Symantec directly using any of the communication means outlined at the end of this statement. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

By displaying the TRUSTe "Trustmark," we let you know: 

  * What personal information is gathered, stored, tracked or used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * How you can correct inaccuracies in the information

This Privacy Statement applies to all Web sites owned by Symantec that display the Symantec or the Norton logo, except for the sites referred to in section 1.2 below and for Web sites hosted by third parties authorized to display the Symantec name and/or corporate logo.

### 1.0 Privacy Statement Structure and Related Documents

### 1.1 Contents

There are related documents, which supplement this Privacy Statement; please note that this document prevails in the event of any inconsistency: 

  * Privacy Facts Statement: This is a short and less complicated summary of our privacy practices; in the event of any discrepancy, this Privacy Statement shall apply.
  * Social Media Privacy Policy This is a policy respecting the privacy of information in ‘user-generated content’ sites and services that Symantec may from time to time offer; it addresses the issues particular to sites where Symantec does not generate the content but allows users and customers to create content.
  * Product and Services Privacy Notices: Symantec has notices that relate to the particular collection and use of personal information that occurs when users subscribe to, purchase, or use our software or services, and are dependent on the technologies and purposes of those products and services. In those cases, the specific privacy notices govern the collection, use, disclosure, and retention of personal information:
  * LiveUpdate Privacy Policy: Because of the manner in which LiveUpdate operates to collect and the type of information it collects, LiveUpdate has its own Privacy Policy.
  * Norton Community Watch Privacy Policy: This is a policy respecting the collection of information through user submissions to the Norton Community Watch; it addresses issues relating to the collection of information including personally identifiable information.
  * [Norton Online Family Privacy Policy](https://onlinefamily.norton.com/familysafety/privacypolicy.jsp): This is a policy respecting the collection and use of personal information in respect to the OnlineFamily.Norton services.

Symantec has a global policy, which establishes a foundation for the privacy of all Personal Information used by Symantec worldwide. The policy states Symantec’s operational principles for managing privacy.

These policies have the following scope: 

  * It applies to all Personal Information collected by Symantec, electronically or manually. The requirements of the Policy are supplemented by business specific privacy processes.
  * The Policy applies to employees, officers, and directors of Symantec and its subsidiaries worldwide.

### 3.1 Personal Information Collection and Use

You may choose to provide personal information through our web sites. Here are the ways in which you may provide the information and the types of information you may submit. We also provide below some information on how we may use the information.

> **Contact Us**  
>  If you communicate with us through the “Contact Us” link on our web sites, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address and telephone number so we can respond to your questions and comments. We also may use the information you provide to evaluate the quality of our products.
> 
> **Request a Quote**  
>  If you request a quote from us, we ask you to provide details such as your name, email address, telephone number and details of the relevant product. We use your details to prepare and send you a quote. You may also choose to provide additional comments and requests through our free text box.
> 
> **Purchase, Registering a Product or Subscribe to a Product or a Service, or Creating an Account**  
>  If you submit an order on-line with us, we will ask you for information necessary to complete the transaction – such as your name, address, and credit card number, and to allow you to purchase and download products, obtain access to service and technical support, or otherwise utilize products or services that you have selected, as well as technical data concerning your computer or traffic data incidental to your Internet connection. Additionally, you may be asked to set up an account with us in order to obtain software, establish entitlement to upgrades and updates, configure products and services, and access reports and information on the performance of such products and services, etc. This may require you to provide relevant information such as email addresses, physical addresses, IM addresses, and IP address ranges. The processing and transfer of the data are limited to the following purposes: fulfillment of your order(s)/contract(s), extension/delivering product updates/service-subscriptions or licenses, product/service registration, activation and configuration, processing change requests which you may request from time to time, customer and technical support as you may request it from time to time, processing license renewals as you may request it from time to time, automatically processing license renewals if you elect automatic renewal of your software license subscription and internal (compliance) audits and fraud prevention.
> 
> **Request Technical Support**  
>  If you request technical support online, we will ask you for information necessary to complete the transaction – such as your name, address and information about your computer hardware, software and the nature of the problem you are experiencing. Additionally, if required to facilitate support, we may with your permission [conduct an interactive session in which a Symantec technical support assumes control of your computer. No information is retained from such sessions beyond information to substantiate that such session(s) took place. Information concerning technical issues may be retained to provide you with continuing support; generally, the information and knowledge obtained from such support, though not linked to you personally, may be made available to technical and product specialists in order to improve our products or provide similar solutions to similar technical issues encountered by other Symantec customers.
> 
> **Marketing Communications**  
>  In addition to the purposes described above, we may also use your data to provide you with information about products and services which may be of interest to you. Contact details, including phone numbers and email addresses, may be used to contact you. You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for such marketing purposes. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, you can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking/un-checking (as applicable) certain boxes on the web pages and/or forms on which we collect your data. You can also exercise this right at any time by changing your communication choices as described in section 4.2 below.
> 
> **Subscribe to a Website Forum or Networking Site**  
>  Symantec operates forums, web sites and related information services to better assist its customers in using its products and services, discuss technical issues, and share experience and knowledge. To permit you to obtain access to these information services, to assist us in creating content that is relevant to you, and to improve your experience on our Web site, including helping you quickly find software, services or product information important to you we collect information on your name and e-mail address, and keep track of your preferences concerning the display or location of relevant information. We utilize the information obtained from these sites to improve our products and services. You should be aware that any information you provide in public forums may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from any forum, contact us at [privacy@symantec.com](mailto:privacy@symantec.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
> 
> **Subscribe to a Newsletter, Receive Product or Technical Alerts**  
>  You may wish to receive information about virus alerts, product upgrades, new products, services, newsletters, informative emails, and research on future product ideas or improvements. If so, you will be asked to provide your name and e-mail address. If there is any use beyond contacting you using such information, you will be advised of the intended uses at the point that you are being asked to provide such contact information.
> 
> **Transactional Emails**  
>  We may from time to time send you transactional emails such as order confirmations or information on service related issues. Because these emails are not promotional in nature you are not able to unsubscribe from these transactional emails.
> 
> **Enter a Contest, Receive Product or Service Information, Offers or Promotions**  
>  To provide you with contests, promotions or special offers that may be of interest to you, you may be asked to provide us with your name, address and e-mail address information, as well as to confirm that you are of the age of majority in the jurisdiction in which you reside. You may be asked to provide additional information to better understand you and possibly your organizations’ needs and experiences, opinions, as well as your experience or feedback in order to qualify for such contests or promotions. We will also use your personal information to award prizes if applicable. If there is any use beyond contacting you with such information, you will be advised of the intended uses at the point that you are being asked to provide such contact information.
> 
> **Soliciting your Opinion, Feedback or Test Software**  
>  To assist us in creating better products and services to meet your needs, we may solicit your opinions and feedback concerning our software and services; you may be asked to provide e-mail address information, as well as name, postal address, occupation and the name of your organization, if you have not already done so, as well as the opinions and feedback itself.
> 
> **Careers**  
>  You may be able to submit your resume and other information online to apply for a job with Symantec. The information you provide in connection with your job search will be maintained in a database that is managed by a third party service provider we have retained to help us conduct recruitment-related activities. Our service provider is authorized to use the information only in connection with hosting, managing and maintaining our resume database. We use the information you submit to evaluate your interest in employment and to contact you regarding possible employment with the company.
> 
> **Refer-A-Friend**  
>  If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Symantec does not store your friend’s name and email address after sending the one-time email. Note that this is not available in jurisdictions where this method of referral is prohibited, such as the European Union.
> 
> **Information from Other Sources**  
>  Information we collect about you may be aggregated with information we receive from third parties.
> 
> **Data Aggregation**  
>  In general, we may combine and aggregate data we receive from various sources, including but not limited to user generated profiles, cookies, email analytics, etc.

You make the decision whether to proceed with any activity that requests personal information. If you do not wish to provide the requested information, however, you may not be able to complete the transaction or functionality on the site if the information is essential to complete the transaction or functionality.

#### About cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit or certain emails you open. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide business and marketing information to the owners of the site. Cookies also enable a web site to tailor information presented to you based on your browsing preferences, such as language and geographical region. For more detailed information about cookies visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

#### Use of cookies by Symantec

The cookies used on this site are described according to the following cookie categories:

 **Strictly Necessary.** These cookies do not collect any information about you that could be used for marketing purposes or to track your navigation on other websites.

 **Performance.** These cookies do not collect any information about you that could be used for marketing purposes, to track your navigation on other websites, or to send you targeted ads. _These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website, for instance which pages they go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies you._

**Functionality.** We do not use functionality cookies to target you with advertisements on other websites. These cookies allow the website to detect some features of your device, for instance if you are using a mobile to navigate, and to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can be used to remember changes made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that can be customized. They may also be used to provide services you asked for such as watching a video, initiating a chat, or commenting on a blog. These cookies cannot track browsing activity on other websites.

 **Targeting Cookies.** Targeting cookies on our sites are linked to services provided by third parties. Our third party provides these services in return for recognizing that you have visited our website. 

If you have registered your product and created a Norton Account, we will match the information gathered from our cookies with any information you have given us about yourself, or that is stored in your Norton Account, or that we have otherwise collected about you for the purposes explained in this Privacy Statement. 

**You can opt out from these cookies by adjusting your browser settings to reject cookies. If you have previously visited our websites, you may also have to delete any existing cookies from your browser.**

 **Many of our cookies are functionality cookies and some of these cookies are managed for us by third parties. You can control the use of these cookies through your browser settings, but if you opt out from them, we may be unable to offer some services or support and we may also be unable to remember your preferences or that you did not want a certain service.**

### Other Opt-out options

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Keeping track of your login
  * Putting merchandise in your cart
  * Remembering information entered on online forms when you navigate to different pages in a single web browser session

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

  * ASP.NET_SessionId
  * CartGuid
  * lifb1d8525d94d660bc8f92b8419fd5ae1 (dynamic name)
  * showexpert

### Performance Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Web and Video Analytics
  * To determine which server is delivering content to you
  * To track active sessions
  * To determine if cookies are enabled
  * To measure visitors’ response time
  * To identify how many times you visited us, and which products were purchased at what price

#### Performance Cookies (First Party)

  * _g_c
  * _g_u
  * Akamai_ AnalyticsMetrics_clientId
  * AkamaiAnalytics_BrowserSessionId
  * AkamaiAnalytics_VisitCookie
  * AkamaiAnalytics_VisitIsPlaying
  * AkamaiAnalytics_VisitLastCloseTime
  * AkamaiAnalyticsDO_bitRateBucketsCsv
  * AkamaiAnalyticsDO_visitMetricsCsv
  * AkamaiAnalyticsDO_visitStartTime
  * bizProdScrollVertical
  * clientLastHTimes
  * clientLastPTimes
  * Enterprise
  * last_topic_viewed
  * mbox
  * NREUM
  * s_cc
  * s_pers
  * s_sess
  * s_sq
  * s_sv_112_p1
  * s_sv_112_s1
  * s_vi
  * SESSfb1d8525d94d660bc8f92b8419fd5ae1 (dynamic name)
  * v1st

#### Performance Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
.ic-live.com | Sid1168  
.ic-live.com | icpid  
beacon-1.newrelic.com | JSESSIONID  
sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickSiteContainerID_71097838  
tubemogul.com | _tmid  
korrelate.net | adsuu  
  
### Functionality Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Provide proactive live chat sessions to offer you support
  * Store currency selection
  * Store country and language of the page
  * Store the locale you have chosen
  * Store value of podcast channel selected by the visitor
  * Detecting initial bandwidth capability
  * Detecting mobile and redirecting
  * Detect Geo IP information
  * Identify source of the marketing campaign that referred the users

#### Functionality Cookies (First Party)

  * filter_state_
  * IS3_GSV
  * IS3_History
  * lpCloseInvite
  * marketing (to identify campaign source)
  * userlocale

#### Functionality Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
Sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickCHATKEY  
Sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickKEY  
Sales.liveperson.net | LivePersonID  
  
### Targeting Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Offer white papers and chats based on frequency of visits, pages visited, and other activity information taken over multiple sessions.
  * Detect your region via your IP address.
  * Drop a 'do-not-track' cookie for European users.
  * Track web behavior across Symantec websites such as campaign interactions; shopping cart activity; clicks on certain links, including but not limited to videos, white papers, chat buttons and social media interactions; etc, in order to provide you a more customized web experience, and to better promote our products and services.
  * Display pop-ups to download white papers or chat with a sales representative.
  * Serve banner ads after you have visited our websites or have opened an email. Users can prevent tracking by clicking the relevant button on certain banner ads, in addition to other options described in section 3.2.
  * Show display ads after you have visited our sites or have opened an email.

#### Targeting Cookies (First Party)

  * _adnx_
  * _dtm_token_
  * _mkto_ _trk

#### Targeting Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
.tubemogul.com | _tmpi  
com-verisign.netmng.com | evo5_VERISIGN  
http://www.googleadservices.com/pagead/ | conversion.js  
IgnitionOne | IgnitionOne  
  
#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

  * None on this site.

### Performance Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Web Analytics
  * Identify which campaign or sub-campaign directed you to our websites
  * Identify which ad directed you to our websites
  * Identify how many times you visited us, and which products were purchased at what price

#### Performance Cookies (First Party)

  * campaign
  * mlc
  * s_pers
  * s_sess
  * subcampaign

#### Performance Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickSiteContainerID_1573289  
korrelate.net | adsuu  
  
### Functionality Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Store country and language of the page
  * Provide proactive live chat sessions to offer you support
  * Prevent automatic live chat pop-up notifications, once you have closed the chat

#### Functionality Cookies (First Party)

  * culture
  * detected
  * lpCloseInvite

#### Functionality Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
Sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickCHATKEY  
Sales.liveperson.net | HumanClickKEY  
Sales.liveperson.net | LivePersonID  
  
### Targeting Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Detect your region via your IP address.
  * Drop a 'do-not-track' cookie for European users.
  * Track web behavior across Symantec websites such as campaign interactions; shopping cart activity; clicks on certain links, including but not limited to videos, white papers, chat buttons and social media interactions; etc, in order to provide you a more customized web experience, and to better promote our products and services.

#### Targeting Cookies (First Party)

  * _mkto_ _trk

### 3.2.3. Cookies on SMB Micro-sites including, but not limited to, the following:

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Purpose

  * Track the session ID to serve appropriate content

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies (First Party)

  * ASP.NET_SessionId

### Performance Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Web Analytics
  * Testing
  * Reporting campaign performance including but not limited to click-through, visits, page-views, paths, downloads, registrations, video plays, and bounce rates
  * Measuring country and marketing vehicle performance against the micro-sites and wider Symantec.com site
  * Video Analytics such as identifying new users or number of unique users on our sites
  * Monitor session counts for an application
  * Identify how many times you visited us, and which products were purchased at what price

#### Performance Cookies (First Party)

  * mbox
  * s_cc
  * s_pers
  * s_sess
  * s_sq
  * s_sv_112_p1
  * s_sv_112_s1
  * s_vi

#### Performance Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
beacon-1.newrelic.com | JSESSIONID  
tubemogul.com | _tmid  
korrelate.net | adsuu  
  
### Functionality Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Bookmark a site, the first time you have explicitly opted to do so
  * Store your video selection
  * Serve you video content

#### Functionality Cookies (First Party)

  * BC_BANDWIDTH
  * sym090_bookmark
  * Video_ID
  * Video_Num

### Targeting Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Detect your region via your IP address.
  * Drop a 'do-not-track' cookie for European users.
  * Track web behavior across Symantec websites such as campaign interactions; shopping cart activity; clicks on certain links, including but not limited to videos, white papers, chat buttons and social media interactions; etc, in order to provide you a more customized web experience, and to better promote our products and services.

**Targeting Cookies (First Party)**

  * _mkto_ _trk

### 3.2.4 Cookies on Norton.com (EU)

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Keeping track of your login
  * Remembering information entered on online forms when you navigate to different pages in a single web browser session
  * Identifying the server that is provisioning the service
  * Verifying that a session has ended

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies (First Party)

  * JSESSIONID
  * BIGipServerpool_now-prd1.norton.com
  * SSE

### Performance Cookies

#### Purposes

We use Performance Cookies for the following purposes: 

  * Web and Video Analytics
  * To determine which server is delivering content to you
  * To track active sessions
  * To measure visitors’ response time and measure performance
  * To verify which Symantec products are installed on your machine and to consolidate related information

#### Performance Cookies (First Party)

  * TLID
  * es
  * pr
  * tp
  * s_sess
  * s_pers

#### Performance Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
Symantec.com | s_vi  
tubemogul.com | _tmid  
  
### Functionality Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Store country and language of the page
  * Store the locale you have chosen
  * Detecting initial bandwidth capability
  * Detecting mobile and redirecting
  * Identify source of the marketing campaign or program that referred you

#### Functionality Cookies (First Party)

  * COUNTRY
  * LANGUAGE
  * PROGRAMID
  * PROGRAM_TYPE

#### Functionality Cookies (Third Party)

  * None on this site.

### Targeting Cookies

### 3.2.5 Cookies on Buy.Norton.com

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Keeping track of your login
  * Remembering information entered on online forms when you navigate to different pages in a single web browser session
  * Identifying the server that is provisioning the service
  * Verifying that a session has ended

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

  * ASP.NET_SessionID
  * BIGipServerbuy1_prd_SSL
  * BIGipServerbuy2_prd_SSL
  * BIGipServersomain-int
  * Newproducts
  * RemoveProducts
  * Opencart
  * AKNORT
  * JSESSIONID
  * Thx_guid

### Performance Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Web and Video Analytics
  * To determine which server is delivering content to you
  * To track active sessions
  * To measure visitors’ response time and measure performance
  * To verify which Symantec products are installed on your machine and to consolidate related information
  * To test site functionalities and design
  * Identify which campaign or sub-campaign directed you to our websites
  * Identify which ad directed you to our websites
  * Identify which affiliate directed you to our site
  * To identify how many times you visited us, and which products were purchased at what price

#### Performance Cookies

  * adsuu (korrelate.net)
  * event69
  * s_cc
  * s_vi
  * s_eVar63
  * s_eVar65
  * s_eVar70
  * s_nr
  * s_prop22
  * s_sq
  * tp
  * _utma (Google Analytics)
  * _utmb (Google Analytics)
  * _utmc (Google Analytics)
  * _utmz (Google Analytics)
  * LCLK
  * PBLP
  * S
  * Uid
  * Bh
  * es
  * mbox
  * tt

### Functionality Cookies

  * COUNTRY
  * LANGUAGE
  * PROGRAMID
  * PROGRAM_TYPE
  * PR
  * org.springframework.web.servlet.i18n.CookieLocaleResolver.LOCALE
  * _atuvc
  * Psc
  * Uid
  * Uit
  * Uvc

### Functionality Cookies

  * COUNTRY
  * LANGUAGE
  * PROGRAMID
  * PROGRAM_TYPE
  * PR
  * org.springframework.web.servlet.i18n.CookieLocaleResolver.LOCALE
  * _atuvc
  * Psc
  * Uid
  * Uit
  * Uvc

### Targeting Cookies

#### Purpose

  * Serve banner ads after you have visited our website. Users can prevent tracking by clicking the relevant button on the banner ads, in addition to other options described in section 3.2.

### Targeting Cookies (First Party)

### Targeting Cookies (Third Party)

**Cookie** | **Host**  
---|---  
pluto | fastclick.net  
fastclick | fastclick.net  
  
### 3.2.6 Cookies on Micro-sites, including but not limited to:

### Strictly Necessary Cookies

#### Purpose

  * Remember the user has filled in the required profile form to reach the protected downloads requested by the user, for a particular browser session. The form information is also stored in the session cookie, along with the user’s assigned unique ID.
  * Maintain a session with the SymNation application server.
  * Track the gamification activity on SymNation, such as badges/challenges, Symcoins, levels, etc.

### Strictly Necessary Cookies (First Party)

### Strictly Necessary Cookies (Third Party)

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
Second2 | Symphony  
  
### Performance Cookies

  * Omniture Web Analytics Suite including test and targeting, reporting campaign performance including but not limited to click-throughs, visits, page-views, paths, downloads, registrations, video plays, and bounce rates. This data is used to measure country and marketing vehicle performance against the micro-sites and wider Symantec.com site. This data is also used to improve future campaign performance.
  * Video Analytics such as identifying new users or number of unique users on our sites
  * Monitor session counts for an application
  * Identify how many times you visited us, and which products were purchased at what price

#### Performance Cookies (First Party)

  * mbox
  * s_cc
  * s_pers
  * s_sess
  * s_sq
  * s_sv_112_p1
  * s_sv_112_s1
  * s_vi

#### Performance Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
beacon-1.newrelic.com | JSESSIONID  
tubemogul.com | _tmid  
korrelate.net | adsuu  
  
### Functionality Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Remembers the user has filled in the required profile form to reach the protected downloads, for up to 30 days after the browser session has been closed.
  * Remembers the FAQ page expansion and selections on SymNation.

#### Functionality Cookies (First Party)

  * /faq.pspfirsttimelaod

#### Functionality Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
Second2 |  Personal_UID  
  
#### Targeting Cookies

#### Purposes

  * Track user activity on Symantec sites resulting from search engine marketing, in order to improve future search campaigns based on location (IP address), number of visits, conversion rate, and other analytics.

#### Targeting Cookies (Third Party)

**Host** | **Cookie**  
---|---  
www.marinsm.com | msuuid  
  
### 3.3 Web Beacons

Symantec may use Web Beacons - also known as single pixel or clear GIFs - on its web sites to analyze traffic patterns such as the frequency of use of particular parts of the site. The data collected helps us learn what information is of most interest to our customers and what offers our customers would most like to see. If you do not want to assist Symantec in improving its Web sites, you can “opt-out” of this web sites analysis by disabling JavaScript on your computer. If you disable JavaScript, some of the features on our web sites will not work.

Symantec may also use web beacons in promotional email messages to determine whether the message was opened and acted on. We may use this information on email response to develop future promotions you may enjoy. For these purposes, some of our Web beacons are tied to your e-mail address.

Except for the email address you have previously provided, the information we collect does not identify you. To modify your Norton privacy options, visit [here](https://www-secure.symantec.com/custserv/cgi-bin/cs_privacy_dyn.cgi).

Symantec may also use third party scripts on our sites to optimize the effectiveness of Symantec's ads appearing on other parties' sites. The information collected is not personally identifiable and is limited to the minimum information necessary to optimize effectiveness. Symantec has no access or control of any third party tracking technologies.

### 3.4 Flash LSOs

Third parties with whom we partner use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences for audio control.

### 4.1 Opt-in and Opt-out

In jurisdictions where your consent is required at the point of collection before any sharing of your information can take place, you will be given the option to opt-in before such information is being shared, and to opt-in to the transfer of your contact information to a third party.

In other jurisdictions, we may offer you these choices at the time you give us your information, or subsequently through ‘opt-out’ mechanisms.

### 4.2 Communication Choices

If you are on a Symantec web page that requires personal information to be submitted but does not offer communication choices, or if you would like to change your preferences for information that you have previously provided, please use one of the communication channels at the bottom of this statement (see section 11 for details).

### 4.3 Other Privacy Considerations

Please remember that information you submit in a discussion groups or forums, like "Ask Symantec", will be deemed public information and will not be kept as confidential. There is a risk in such communication venues that information can be collected and used by others. Please be careful and responsible when you are participating in such discussion groups or forums. For further details, please see our Social Media Privacy Policy.

### 4.4 Updating or Correcting Your Personal Information

You have the right to update or correct or remove your personal information. If you believe that Symantec does not have your most current personal information, you can update it at your Norton Account, at your Symaccount or through the other communication channels at the bottom of this notice. If requested, and to the extent permissible by applicable law relating to the retention of records or otherwise not required for valid business purposes (such as fulfillment of transactions), you may request that we use our best efforts to remove such data from Symantec repositories.

Symantec will respond to access requests within 30 days.

### 5.1 Transferring Information

Since Symantec is a global company, we provide company information to our worldwide offices, with information processing taking place in many countries. The personal information that you have provided to us, for the purposes set out above, will be transferred to servers in the United States, and there may be further transfers to other countries in which Symantec has operations, or to our outside contractors for the collection, transferring, storage and processing of your information for the purposes outlined above. In respect to transfers from the European Economic Area to the United States or elsewhere, Symantec has data transfer agreements in place if and as required by the data privacy authorities in European countries from where such transfers of personal information are being made.

### 5.2 Sharing Information

From time to time, and in jurisdictions where it is permitted, we may provide your information to [Symantec Partners](http://www.symantec.com/partners/programs/index.jsp) to communicate to you information or offers about products or services that they believe are important to you or your business. If you prefer that we not provide your information to our business partners, you may let us know using one of the methods described in this Statement, Symantec provides a number of ways for you to ‘opt-out’ of receiving additional information from us or having us provide your personal information to our partners by ‘opt-out’ options provided at the point of collection, through e-mail notices, or through other preference management that may be available depending on the service or web-site.

If you do not wish to continue receiving our e-mail newsletters or bulletins you can opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to the "unsubscribe" address in the body of the email.

### 5.3 Third Parties

In addition, Symantec may retain the services of outside contractors to provide services for us (e.g. ship products, provide technical support, or handle order processing).

For example, you may decide to purchase a license to a number of Symantec software products online in a downloadable format by way of Electronic Software Delivery (ESD) or in a CD format from one of Symantec’s authorized online resellers. If you elect to purchase a software license through one of Symantec’s authorized online resellers, your personal data will need to be shared between the Symantec reseller (as your vendor) and Symantec (as the software manufacturer and licensor). Furthermore, in order to manage purchases and license renewals by Symantec customers, Symantec will need to share your personal information with a billing system service provider. Such service provider will process data of Symantec’s customers only on behalf of Symantec. (These examples are not exhaustive, and may change from time to time). 

We require that all such contractors keep the personal information of our customers secure and confidential. We have contractually bound third parties to such restrictions and require that these contractors provide for appropriate technical and organizational measures to secure the data, that they use personal information only on behalf of Symantec and that they do not share personal information with others or use your personal information for their own marketing purposes.

### 5.4 Legal Disclosures

Please be advised that in certain instances, it may be necessary for Symantec to disclose your personal information to government officials or otherwise as required by applicable law. No personal information will be disclosed to any law enforcement agency or governmental agency except in response to: 

  * A subpoena, warrant or other process issued by a court of competent jurisdiction;
  * A legal process having the same consequence as a court-issued request for information, in that Symantec would be in breach of local law were it to refuse to provide such information, and it or its officers, executive or employees would be subject to liability for failing to honor such legal process, provided there is a legal basis to do so, or,
  * Where such disclosure is necessary for Symantec to enforce its legal rights pursuant to the laws of the jurisdiction from which such information was gathered, and there is a legal basis to do so.

We have taken appropriate security measures, consistent with international information practices, to protect your personal information. These measures include, on our web sites and Internet-enabled technologies, administrative, technical, physical and procedural steps to protect your data from misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, loss, alteration, or destruction. These measures include:

> _Physical safeguards_ , such as locked doors and file cabinets, controlled access to our facilities, and secure destruction of media containing personal information;
> 
> _Technology safeguards_ , such as use of Symantec anti-virus and endpoint protection software, encryption, and monitoring of our systems and data centers to ensure compliance with our security policies, and in particular, credit card information is transmitted using secure socket layer (SSL) encryption;
> 
> _Organizational safeguards_ , through training and awareness programs on security and privacy, to ensure employees understand the importance and means by which they must protect personal information, as well as through privacy policies and standards that govern how Symantec treats personal information.

### 7.1 Non-Personal Information We Collect

We collect certain aggregate and non-personal information when users visit our web sites. Aggregate and non-personal information does not relate to a single, identifiable visitor. It tells us information such as how many users visited our sites and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our web sites to our visitors.

We collect this information either through “cookie” technology or with “web beacons,” as explained above.

### 7.4 Web Site Traffic

Through our various tracking methods discussed above and using log files, we may track domain names, IP addresses, and browser types from people who visit our site. We use this information to track aggregate traffic patterns throughout Symantec’s Web site. Such information is not correlated with any personal information. 

Symantec collects and retains, for a limited period of time, internet protocol (IP) address information, of its customers, for the following purposes: 

  * subscription and registration,
  * to provide technical support;
  * to obtain geolocation information;
  * and to secure our networks and systems.

IP addresses collected by Symantec are primarily traffic data, which is not necessarily personal information. Symantec does not have the means to reasonably and authoritatively link an IP address to an identifiable individual. Registration of a product does create a unique computer identifier, which is linked to an IP address at the time of registration; however, IP addresses are usually assigned dynamically and therefore are temporary, and may be behind network address translation, and are often capable of falsification (spoofing).

At the Symantec Web sites, there are a number of links to companies with whom we have a relationship. Symantec is not responsible for the privacy practices of our business partners. We encourage you to read their privacy statements, as they may differ from ours.

We also link to co-branded Web sites that are maintained by Symantec and one or more of our business partners who are collecting your information pursuant to their own policies and purposes.

We encourage you to read the privacy policies on any co-branded site to which you link for information on the privacy practices of that site.

In the event there is a major change to Symantec's privacy practices, a prominent notice will be posted on our Web site. If the change involves the use of your personally identifiable information, the notice will contain instructions on how you can opt-out of such use.

Symantec has created a Privacy Program Office, which is part of Legal and Public Affairs. If you have any questions or comments concerning this Statement, or if you would like to change your communication preferences, update or review the personal information we have about you, or withdraw your consent for the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, please contact us using one of the options below: 

  1. Customer Profile Form at: <https://www-secure.symantec.com/custserv/cgi-bin/cs_privacy_dyn.cgi>
  2. Customer Support in your country or region – by telephone, e-mail, or regular mail;
  3. Through Symantec’s Privacy Department: 

> Symantec Corporation - Privacy Program Office  
>  350 Ellis Street  
>  PO Box 7011  
>  Mountain View, CA 94043  
>  U.S.A  
>  Telephone: 1-650-527-8000   
> Email: [privacy@symantec.com](mailto:privacy@symantec.com)

Different countries, states, and other entities may require specific policies to be provided, and so, will only apply to you provided you live in the jurisdiction set out in the sub-sections below.

### 12.1 North America

### 12.1.1 TRUSTe

Symantec is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program as noted above, which is applicable solely to North America.

### 12.1.2 Your California Privacy Rights

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Symantec who are California residents to request certain information regarding Symantec’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To request such information, please contact us using one of the options listed above in section 11.0.

### 12.2 European Economic Area

In respect to data transfers from the European Economic Area, to the United States or to other countries outside the European Economic Area, Symantec has taken steps to ensure adequate protection for such data transfers in accordance with European and national data protection legislation. For example, Symantec has entered into appropriate data transfer agreements based on the model clauses approved by the European Commission to provide adequate protection for data transfers between Symantec entities and between Symantec and third parties located outside the European Economic Area.

### 12.2.1 Germany

In transferring your information to Symantec, you understand that your name, postal address, phone number, E-mail address, VAT ID (optional), company name (optional), and information about selected product(s), will be transferred from our online store to the producer and licensor Symantec Corporation (350 Ellis Street, Mountain View, CA 94043, U.S.A.), Symantec Limited (Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland) (Billing, Shipping) und Symantec (Deutschland) GmbH, Wappenhalle, Konrad-Zuse-Platz 2-5, D-81829 München, **[www.symantec.com](http://www.symantec.com/ "http://www.symantec.com/")**  
(German consumer contact and support).

Further your payment details (including credit card number, expiry date, sort code, name and address of bank), and order ID will be transferred to Symantec Corporation in the United States and Symantec Limited in Ireland.
